Guide to the Frank Espada photographs and papers, 1946-2010 and undated, bulk 1964-2000 RL.00367
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Other Photographic Work, 1954-1974; 10 prints
  - Finished Prints
    - Man by a fence, Washington, D.C., 1975 (Box 54, Image RL. 00367-P-0324)
      Image dimensions: 13 3/4 x 20 inches; mount dimensions: 20 x 24 inches
    - Abuelita in the Cloisters, New York, 1959 (Box 55, Image RL. 00367-P-0329)
      Image dimensions: 19 1/2 x 14 3/4 inches; mount dimensions: 28 x 22 inches
    - East New York, 1963 (Box 55, Image RL. 00367-P-0330)
      Image dimensions: 12 3/4 x 19 7/8 inches; mount dimensions: 28 x 22 inches
- Negatives (closed to use), 1964-1997; 2.5 Linear Feet 5 boxes Approximately 5500 35 mm negative strips
  The arrangement of the negatives roughly parallels the structure of the photographic projects series, following the original contact sheet numbering system.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Negatives are closed to use.
  Prints or contact sheet images exist for most of the negative frames; additionally, a group of selected Espada images is available online through Duke Digital Collections.
  Please contact the Rubenstein Library in advance for assistance in using this collection.
  These are the original negatives from which Espada developed out contact sheets, work prints, and finished prints. Some may represent images not found elsewhere in the collection, though most seem to have corresponding contacts sheets and in most cases, work prints and exhibit prints.
  The predominant format is 35 mm safety film strips cut from the original rolls. In almost all cases the roll numbers and dates have been preserved, as are the original titles as assigned by the photographer. Some rolls are not present in the collection; these have been noted where possible.
  - Chamorro Documentary Project negatives, 1989-1990; 4 folders Approximately 1356 negative strips
    Negatives are closed to use. Prints or contact sheet images exist for most of the negative frames; additionally, a group of selected images is available online through Duke Digital Collections.
    - Chamorro festival, Vallejo, California, 1989: C/S 1-10 (Box 67)
    - Micronesia: 1-50, 1990 (Box 67)
    - Micronesia; 51-118, 1990 (Box 67)
    - Micronesia: 119-192, 1990 (Box 67)
    - Chamorro exhibit negatives, circa 1990 (Box 67)
  - Civil Rights / Community Activism projects negatives, 1964-1997; 6 folders Approximately 708 negatives strips
    - Albany, N.Y.; CORE, Brooklyn (Ollie Leeds, Isah Bronson); City Hall demo, NAACP; School boycott; School boycott 2 (Malcolm): CR 1-33, 1964-1956 (Box 67)
      Missing: CR 1-3, 8, 9, 13, 16, 26, 27
    - ISH campaign / Betancourt lunch program campaign, Bronx: 1-26, 1984 June (Box 67)
      missing: 11-12
    - Single Room Occupancy (SRO) Project, Mission Agenda, San Francisco: SRO 1-18, 1997 (Box 68)
      Missing SRO4.
    - Real Alternatives Program (RAP): 1-30, 1985-1986 (Box 68)
    - Solivan's [Anibal Solivan Roman Jr.] campaign for State Assembly, East Harlem, N.Y.: 1-12, 1974 October (Box 68)
    - Quest International - Berkeley, San Jose, Esperanza: various rolls numbers (Box 68)
  - HIV/AIDS projects negatives, 1989-1992; 6 folders Approximately 880 negative strips
    - O.S.Y. Youth Project: OSY 1-38, 1989 (Box 68)
    - Joey Benko: C/S 1-6, 13, 14, 1991 (Box 68)
    - Garrett Humphrey and Family: C/S 10-12, 15-20, 1992 (Box 68)
    - Y.E.S. / Sex for Crack: 1-6, 1989 (Box 68)
    - Y.E.S. - HIV/AIDS Prevention: 1-45, 1989-1990 (Box 68)
      Missing numbers 6, 40.
    - Y.E.S. - HIV/AIDS Prevention: 46-97, 1989-1990 (Box 68)
      Missing 51, 53, 73, 80-82, 85.
  - Puerto Rican Diaspora Project negatives, 1976-1989; 3 boxes Approximately 3000 negative strips
    - California, 1981: CA 1-32 (Box 69)
      Missing CA 3, 6, 16, 18-21, 24, 25, 30, 31.
    - Dia de San Juan, Cabrillo Beach, CA, 1976: 1-12 (Box 69)
    - Chicago, 1982: CH 1-37 (Box 69)
      Missing CH 2, 7, 10, 24.
    - Hawaii, 1981: HI 1-39 (Box 69)
      Missing HI 10, 35.
    - Hawaii, 1981: HI 40-70 (Box 69)
      Missing HI 48, 52, 64, 68, 71.
    - Milwaukee, 1983: 1-12 (Box 69)
    - Vineland and Glassboro, New Jersey, 1981: GL 1-16 (Box 69)
      Missing GL 5.
    - New York-Ballet Hispanico, 1981: NY 1-28 (Box 69)
    - New York-Ballet Hispanico, 1981: NY 134-138 (Box 69)
      Missing 135, 139, 140.
    - New York-Puerto Rican Travelling Theatre, 1981: NY 29-37 (Box 70)
    - New York-Museo del Barrio, 1981: NY 38-54 (Box 70)
    - New York-East Harlem Music School, 1980-1981: NY 55-67 (Box 70)
      Missing NY 62.
    - New York-PROMESA, 1980-1981: NY 68-100 (Box 70)
    - New York-Manhattan Valley, 1981: NY 102-110 and NY 141-156 (Box 70)
      Missing 105, 142, 146, 148, 149.
    - New York-Boricua College, 1989: NY 112-118 (Box 70)
      Missing NY 117.
    - New York-United Bronx Parents, 1981: NY 119-133 (Box 70)
    - Pennsylvania: Harrisburg and Lancaster, 1979: PRD 20, 22-25 (Box 70)
    - Pennsylvania, 1981: PA 1-29 (Box 70)
      Missing PA 10.
    - Pennsylvania, 1981: PA 30-88 (Box 70)
      Missing PA 40, 53-58, 61, 63, 71, 73, 83.
    - Planning Grant, 1979: PRD 1-6 (Box 71)
    - Planning Grant, 1979-1980: PRD 8-43 (Box 71)
      Excluding PRD 7, 12, 13, 20, 22-25, 27, 42, 43.
    - Planning Grant, 1979-1980: PRD 44-95 (Box 71)
      Missing PRD 48, 50, 55, 72-75, 77, 79, 81, 84, 90, 91.
    - El Puente Documentary, 1984: 1-25 (Box 71)
    - Puerto Rico-Returning Migrants, 1981: 2-49 (Box 71)
      Missing 14, 16, 26.
    - Puerto Rico-Returning Migrants, 1981: 50-92 (Box 71)
      Missing 55, 66, 86, 87.
    - Puerto Rican Legal Defense Fund, 1982: PRLD 1-10, 17-36, 2C, 5C-10C (Box 71)
    - Washington, DC, 1982: DC 1-34 (Box 71)
- Professional and Personal Papers, 1946-2010; 4.5 Linear Feet 9 boxes
  The Professional and Personal Papers Series offers supporting documentation related to Frank Espada's photographic work and teaching career, with an emphasis on the Puerto Rican Diaspora project. The papers comprise correspondence, writing drafts, notes, research files, statistics, reports, book production files, personal papers, and course materials. They are organized in these series: Chamorro Documentary Project; Civil Rights and Community Activism; HIV/AIDS Projects; Puerto Rican Diaspora Project; Personal Papers; and Teaching Materials.
  The largest group of materials documents the decades-long lifespan of the NEH-funded Puerto Rican Diaspora Project. Files include preliminary research and planning, the grant application, and the administration of the grant, as well as project newsletters, reports, and extensive documentation on the many site visits in the U.S. and Puerto Rico. Multiple folders relate to oral history interviews, including summaries, quotes, and a few transcripts. Another set of files documents exhibit preparation and logistics for the Diaspora exhibits, which traveled to many locations in the U.S. and Puerto Rico over a 15-year period. Other materials include documentation about social and economic conditions in Puerto Rico and the immigrant communities highlighted by Espada in the project.
  The Chamorro Documentary Project materials, dating 1989-1990, include information about the different locations photographed by Espada, as well as notebooks and exhibit materials. Some negatives of exhibit panels were removed for preservation reasons to the Negatives Series.
  The remainder of the Papers Series includes records from other projects relating to civil rights and community activism, both photographic and research-oriented; personal writings by Espada; biographical materials and photographs of Espada; and several boxes of teaching materials, 1990s-2000s, chiefly deriving from his position on the U.C. Berkeley faculty.
  - Chamorro Documentary Project, 1989-1990
    - Documentary correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 58)
    - Expense report, July 1990 (Box 58)
    - Copy-captions, introductions, sections, 1990 (Box 58)
    - Research re: Guam (Box 58)
    - Micronesia, 1990 (Box 58)
    - Exhibit log, July 1990 (Box 58)
    - Photo notebook, 1989-1990 (Box 58)
    - Exhibit brochure (Box 58)
    - Letter from Loling, also known as Laura Marie Toures Souder, 1990 May (Box 58)
    - Guam/Chamorros, 1990 (Box 58)
  - Civil Rights / Community Activism, 1965-2008
    - School boycotts 1964, 2008 (Box 58)
    - Manny, 1965 (Box 58)
    - National Civil Rights Museum (Box 58)
    - Real Alternatives Program (RAP) School, 1986 (Box 58)
    - Quest International report and position paper, 1985-1987 (Box 58)
    - Housing development and neighborhood preservation report, San Francisco, 1989 (Box 58)
  - HIV / AIDS Projects, 1989-1991 and undated
    These paper records document Espada's involvement with outreach and prevention programs related to the HIV/AIDS and street drug crisis of the 1980s and 1990s.
    - AIDS Education for youth (Box 58)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: Mid-city project log, 1989-1990 (Box 58)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: Society article with Espada's photographs, 1990 (Box 58)
    - HIV/AIDS outreach: YES manual for outreach to drug users, 1991 (Box 58)
    - YES Outreach Program to Combat AIDS introduction, 1991 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Puerto Rican Diaspora Project, 1970s-2010; 4 boxes
    Papers relate to the span of Espada's grant-funded Puerto Rican Diaspora Project, beginning from the late 1970s to the end of the 2000s. Materials in the form of memos, correspondence, notes, drafts, publicity, and reports document in detail the stages of research, planning, site visits, interviews, grant administration, exhibits, and book production.
    - Correspondence, 1978-2010, 9 folders (Box 59)
      Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence about drug abuse programs, letters to advisory group members, exhibits, and travel.
    - Memoranda to National Advisory Board members, 1981-1982 (Box 59)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities grant records, 1979-1980; 6 folders (Box 60)
      Includes the award letter from the NEH, as well as correspondence for advisory board members concerning the grant.
    - Site visits: Boston (Box 60)
    - Site visits: Connecticut, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Site visits: Pennsylvania, 4 folders (Box 60)
    - Site visits: Puerto Rico, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Eight interview summaries: Los Angeles, New York, Hawaii, Connecticut (Box 60)
    - Thirteen interview summaries: Connecticut, New York City, Hawaii (Box 60)
    - Quotes extracted from interviews, for book (Box 60)
    - Project update reports (Box 60)
    - Theses on Puerto Rican topics, City University of New York, 1977 (Box 60)
    - Puerto Rican migration paper presented at the Hispanic Mental Health and Human Services Organizations conference, 1980 (Box 60)
    - Drug abuse prevention materials, 1970s (Box 61)
    - Puerto Rican Family Institute, program proposal (Box 61)
    - Newsletter of the Puerto Rican Diaspora Project, three issues (Box 61)
    - PROMESA drug abuse program publicity, photos by Espada (Box 61)
    - Five personal narratives taken from interviews (Box 61)
    - Seven interview summaries and notes (Box 61)
    - Puerto Rican Legal Defense Fund brochure, photos by Espada (Box 61)
    - "Who am I?" article by Espada in Nuestro, 1982 (Box 61)
    - Boricua College 10th Anniversary Report, 1984 (Box 61)
    - "Los Olvidados" exhibit, and theater production, "El mito de Beatriz," 1985 (Box 61)
    - Article on Puerto Rican Diaspora project in Left Curve Magazine, No.12, 1987 (Box 61)
    - Poverty statistics, 1987, 1999 (Box 61)
    - "Where are the voices of protest?", op-ed by Espada, 1989 (Box 61)
    - "Poverty and Puerto Ricans in the U.S.," proposal drafts and letters, 1989-1991 (Box 61)
    - Exhibit materials: publicity, proposals, notes, lists of sites, sponsors, and captions, 1980s-2006; 7 folders (Box 61)
    - "Faces of the Sixties," exhibit brochure from Museo Del Barrio, circa 1976 (Box 61)
    - Faces of the Sixties introduction, 1988 (signed) (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Book production: quotes, captions, notes, drafts, 1987-2006; 4 folders (Box 61)
    - Book production: quotes, captions, interview narratives, editorial process files, 2006; 17 folders (Box 62)
      Includes copy-edit notes, paste-ups, book dummy, notebook chiefly relating to illustrations, book design printout.
    - Clippings about Frank Espada, 1968-1969 (Box 63)
    - Clippings about Hispanic community, 1969-1980s (Box 63)
    - Clippings and articles about Diaspora exhibits, 1981-1990 and undated; 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Proclamations from exhibits, 1985-1991 (Box 63)
    - Felicia Kornbluh's book and materials, Battle for Welfare Rights, 2004 (Box 63)
    - Captions for Puerto Rican Diaspora exhibits, 1990s-2000s (Box 56)
      Large box of caption cards used in various Puerto Rican Diaspora exhibits around the country.
    - Puerto Rican Community Day, formal Boston Proclamation, December 1985 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Posters and other promotional material from Espada's exhibits, particularly from the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Galley sheets with selected reproduced photographic portraits from Diaspora project, 2 Sheets 1 folder Approximately 20x24 inches (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Personal Papers, 1946-2010
    Files and memorabilia assembled by Espada make up this series. The earliest date belongs to an essay written by Espada in 1946 about his own self-identity and the meaning of history. Series includes several pieces of writing by his brother, Martin Espada.
    Other materials speaking to Frank Espada's life and career are found in the Puerto Rican Diaspora subseries of the Papers Series, which includes clippings on his project successes and testimonials about the project, and in the Teaching Series, which includes some biographical/academic information.
    - Plaque with photograph of Espada speaking at a National Association of Puerto Rican Drug Abuse Programs Conference, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 57)
    - Recognition award plaque from the National Association of Puerto Rican Drug Abuse Programs, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 57)
    - "What Democracy Means to Me," third-year history class essay by Espada, 1946 (Box 63)
    - Photographs of Espada, 1969-1977; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Testimonials about Espada, 1999-2003 (Box 63)
    - Thank you notes to Espada, 1980-2010 (Box 63)
    - New York Institute of Photography certificate for Commercial Photography graduation, February 1958 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - New York Institute of Photography certificate for Portrait Photography graduation, June 1958 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - New York Institute of Photography merit award for Portraiture, September 1958 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Honorary Doctor of Arts degree, Herbert H. Lehman College, 2008 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Village Camera Club Outstanding Photographic Achievement certificate, January 1960 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Essays by Martin Espada, 1998-2010 and undated (Box 63)
  - Teaching Materials, 1989-2005; 3 boxes
    Papers relate to courses taught by Espada at U.C. Berkeley in California during the 1990s and 2000s. Of interest are the many introductory essays intended for his students on such topics as aesthetics, the art of the fine print, how to approach a negative, how to think about photography, and Espada's own practice as an artist and technician.
    - Course records and handbooks, 1991-1998; 19 folders (Box 64)
      Includes syllabi, some departmental handouts and instructions, handwritten notes, and detailed printed notes and essays for students on art, photography, and technical issues.
    - Courses and handbooks, 1990s-2005 and undated; 20 folders (Box 65)
      Includes many detailed handbooks written and printed by Espada for his courses on photography and aesthetics. There is a photocopied article on photographer Cartier-Bresson. Also includes anonymous student evaluations on Espada's teaching.
    - Courses and handbooks, 1989-2005 and undated; 11 folders (Box 66)
      Files contain course materials on street photography, portraiture, and other topics. One folder contains slides used in the classroom for portraiture study.
- Audiovisual Materials, 1979-1991 and undated; 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The majority of this series consists of interview cassette tapes 1-129 (a total of 160 interviews) from the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project. There are also three video interviews with Frank Espada.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Original audiovisual recordings are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this collection.
  - Interviews of Frank Espada, 1991 and undated
    Original media recordings are closed to use; copies must be requested in advance.
    - Frank Espada interview, WMHT 17 Arts Panorama, 1991-03-30; 0:28:11 (Box 72, Video-cassette RL00367-VHS-0002, Digital-materials RL00367-SET-0001)
    - Frank Espada interview on diaspora, Visiones #82, La Gente #6, 1983-12-19; 0:39:43 (Box 72, Videotape RL00367-Bmax-0001, Digital-materials RL00367-SET-0001)
    - Frank Espada interview, Frank Espada, Andy Mogg, Introduction, 4 takes, 1990s; 0:34:57 (Box 72, Video-cassette RL00367-VHS-0001, Digital-materials RL00367-SET-0001)
  - Oral History Interviews, 1979-1983
    The oral history audiocassettes have been digitized and are available for reading room use. Click on the Request button to request the specific digital recording using the Duke Digital Repository Item ID. Contact Research Services for further information.
    These 153 oral histories were recorded on audiocassettes from 1979 to 1983 by Frank Espada and teams of assistants during site visits as part of the Puerto Rican Diaspora Project. Interviews vary in length but range from 30 minutes to an hour or more. Portraits of many of the individuals interviewed are also found in the photographs series.
    Interview excerpts, used extensively in the project book publication, add in-depth context to Espada's photographs and research. Summaries of the interviews and handwritten notes on the site visits and individuals are found in the Puerto Rican Diaspora Project subseries of the Papers series.
    - Piniero, Jorge Oakland, CA, 1979-01-05 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0001, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001001)
    - Western Council - Oakland, CA, 1979-01-05 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0002, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001002)
    - Calderon, Mazda C. - Oakland, CA, 1979-01-05 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0002, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001002)
    - Souza, Blasé - Honolulu, HI, 1979-01 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0003, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001003)
    - Evans, Faith - Honolulu, HI, 1979-01-11 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0004, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001004)
    - Faria, John - Honolulu, HI, 1979-01-11 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0004, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001004)
    - Vega, Solomon - Kawai, HI, 1979-01-14 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0005, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001005)
    - Cardona, Pablo - Milwaukee, WI, 1979-12-11 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0006, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001006)
    - Caban, Cristobal - Milwaukee, WI, 1979-12-11 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0006, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001006)
    - Acevedo, Angel - Joint Drug Program, Milwaukee, WI, 1979-12-11 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0007, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001007)
    - Hernandez, Jose - Milwaukee, WI, 1979-12 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0008, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001008)
    - Spanish American Community, 1979-12-13 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0009, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001009)
    - Fernandez, Ricardo; Pineiro, Carlos; Ilar, Pedro - Cleveland, OH, 1979-12-13 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0010, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001010)
    - Jimenez, Cha Cha - Chicago, IL, 1979-12-13 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0010, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001010)
    - Ortiz, Rocky - Lorrain, OH, 1979-12-14 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0011, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001011)
    - Crespo, Ramon - Reading, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0012, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001012)
    - Ortiz Jose - Reading, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0012, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001012)
    - Ponce, Carlos - Reading, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0013, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001013)
    - Crespo Sr., Ramon - Miguel, Reading, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0014, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001014)
    - Centro Hispano - Harrisburg, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0014, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001014)
    - Centro Hispano - Harrisburg, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0015, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001015)
    - Centro Hispano - Harrisburg, PA, 1979-12-26 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0016, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001016)
    - Roman, Ed - Lancaster, PA, 1979-12-28 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0017, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001017)
    - Seda - Lancaster, PA, 1979-12-28 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0017, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001017)
    - Santiago, Ramon - Lancaster, PA, 1979-12 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0018, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001018)
    - El Centro - Lancaster, PA, 1979-12 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0018, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001018)
    - Garcia, Willie; Tuzu, David; Santiago, Grace - PROMESA, Bronx, NY, 1980-01-09 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0019, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001019)
    - Santiago, Grace; Alfredo; Gosman, Enid - PROMESA, Bronx, NY, 1980-01-09 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0019, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001019)
    - Laguna, Mike - Crossroads, New Haven, CT, 1980-01-29 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0020, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001020)
    - del Rio, Gumercindo - JUNTO, New Haven, CT, 1980-01-29 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0020, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001020)
    - Cabrera, Gabriel - JUNTO, New Haven, CT, 1980-01-29 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0021, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001021)
    - Osorio, Menen - New Haven, CT, 1980-01-30 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0021, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001021)
    - Colon, Edith - Burgos Center, Hartford, CT, 1980-01-30 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0022, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001022)
    - Colon, Melvin - Burgos Center, Hartford, CT, 1980-01-30 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0022, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001022)
    - Domenech, Armengol - Burgos Center, Hartford, CT, 1980-01-30 (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00367-CS-0023, Digital-materials Duke Digital Repository Item ID: espau001023)